大家好，感谢你们的到来。
All right everyone.Thanks for coming in.
这门课程叫做"计算机科学教育中缺失的部分"，
This is the Missing Semester of your CS Education
至少我们是这样称呼这门课的。
at least that's what we chose to call the class.
如果你不是来上这门课的话，那么你可能来错地方了。
If you're not here for this class, then you're in the wrong room.
我们将在这里待大约一个小时，来给大家介绍一下这门课的内容。
We will be here for about an hour, just to set your expectations.
首先我想跟大家聊一下我们为什么要开设这门课。
And I want to talk to you a little bit first about why we're doing this class.
这门课源于我们（Anish、Jose和我）在麻省理工学院担任助教时的一个观察，
So, this class stems out of an observation that Anish and Jose and I have made while TA various classes at MIT,
我们发现我们作为计算机科学家都知道,
which is that basically all of us computer scientists we know
计算机在处理重复任务和自动化方面非常出色。
that computers are great at doing these repetitive tasks and automating things.
但是我们通常没有意识到，有很多工具可以使我们的开发过程变得更加高效。
But we often fail to realize that there are lots of tools that can make our own development processes better.
我们可以更好地利用计算机，
We can be a lot more efficient about how we use our computers
将其作为自己的工具，
because we can use the computer as a tool for ourselves,
而不仅仅是用来搭建网站或制作软件等。
not just for building websites or software, those sorts of things.
这门课程是为了解决这个问题，尝试向大家展示一些工具，
And this class is an attempt to address this, is an attempt to show you some of the tools
这些工具可以在你的日常工作、研究和学习中发挥重要的作用。
that you can use to great effect in your day to day, in your research, and in your studies.
这门课程将教授大家如何充分利用你已经了解的工具，
And it's going to be a class where we want to teach you both how to make the most of the tools that you already know,
同时也会向你介绍一些你之前不知道的工具，
but also hopefully teach you about some tools you don't know from before
并教你如何将这些工具结合起来，以让你变得更加强大。
and how to combine those tools to produce more powerful things than you think you might be able to do with what you know today.
这门课程将分为11个一小时的讲座，
The class is going to be structured as a series of 11 one-hour lectures
每个讲座都将涵盖特定的主题。
and each one is gonna cover a particular topic.
你可以查看网站上的课程主题列表，以及每个讲座的日期。
You can see the website, which is also listed there, for the list of lecture topics and what date we'll do each one.
他们大多数会是独立的，
They will mostly be independent,
所以你可以选择参加你感兴趣的讲座，
and so you can sort of show up for the ones that you're interested in,
但我们会假定你一直在跟进，这样当我们到后面的讲座时，
but we will sort of assume that you've been following along so that as we get to later lectures,
我不会再教你例如bash这样的东西。
I'm not going to be teaching you bash all over again, for example.
我们还会在线发布讲座笔记和讲座录像。
We are also going to post both the lecture notes and recordings of the lectures online.
我们还没有确定具体时间，但这将是在讲座之后。
Exactly when we do that we haven't established yet, but it will be after the lectures.
显然，视频必须在讲座之后发布。
Obviously, the videos have to be posted after.
本课程将由我，Jose和Anish一起授课，他们坐在那边，
The class is going to be run by me, Jose, and Anish, each sitting over there,
Jose目前不在这里，但他将主持明天的讲座。
and Jose who is not currently here, but we'll be holding tomorrow's lecture.
请注意，我们将在仅仅11个一小时的讲座中涵盖大量内容，
And keep in mind that we're trying to cover a lot of ground over the course of just 11 one-hour lectures,
所以我们将相对快速地讲解。
and so we will be moving relatively rapidly.
但如果有任何地方你感觉跟不上，一定要停止我们。
But please do stop us if there's anything where you feel like you're not following along.
如果你觉得有些东西希望我们花更多的时间讲解，
If you feel like there's something you wish we would spend more time on,
请随时中断我们提问。
just let us know,please interrupt us with questions.
此外，每次讲座之后，
And also, after each lecture,
我们都在第32栋楼的第9层办公室有办公时间，
we're going to hold office hours on the ninth floor of Building 32,
即在计算机科学楼的Stata Center。
the Stata Center of the computer science building.
如果你来Gates Tower的第9层的休息室，
If you show up in the ninth-floor lounge there and the Gates Tower,
那么你可以来做做我们为每次讲座提供的练习，
then you can come and try some of the exercises that we give for each lecture
或者询问我们关于讲座中讨论的内容
or just ask us other questions about things we've talked about in the lecture
以及如何更高效地使用你的电脑的其他问题。
or other things about using your computer efficiently.
鉴于我们的时间有限，
Due to the limited time that we have available,
我们将无法对所有工具进行详细介绍，
we're not gonna be able to cover all tools in full detail,
所以只会着力讲解有趣的工具以及使用它们的有趣方法。
and so what we'll try to do is highlight interesting tools and interesting ways to use them.
我们不一定会深入探讨所有工具的工作原理或更复杂的用例。
We won't necessarily dig into the deep details about how all of it works or more elaborate use cases.
但如果您有任何相关问题，请随时问我们。
But if you have questions about them, please come ask us about that too.
其中许多工具我们都使用了多年，
Many of these tools are tools that we have used for years,
我们能教你怎么用这些工具倒腾一些有趣的东西,
and we might be able to point you to additional interesting things you can do with them,
所以要充分利用好这次上课的机会.
sort of like take advantage of the fact that we're here.
这节课我不想讲得非常迅速，
This class is going to, I don't wanna say ramped up quickly,
但在今天这个讲座中，
but what's going to happen over the course of this particular lecture is that
我们假定你已经掌握了一些后面的讲座中包含的基础知识，
we'll cover many of the basics that we assume that you will know for the rest of the semester.
比如如何使用你的shell和终端，对于那些对这些工具不熟悉的人，我将在讲座中进行解释。
Things like how to use your shell and your terminal, and I'll explain what those who you're not familiar with them.
然后，我们会迅速进入更高级的工具的讲解以及如何使用它们。
And then we'll pretty quickly ramp up into more advanced tools and how to use them.
你已经可以从讲座笔记中看到我们将要涵盖的主题。
You can already see from the lecture notes the kind of topics that we're going to be covering.
所以，这就是今天的讲座，所以我们今天要讲shell。
And so, that brings us to today's lecture, in which we are going to cover the shell.
当您熟悉的可视化界面无法实现您想要的功能时，
And the shell is going to be one of the primary ways that
shell 将是你与计算机交互的主要方式之一。
you interact with your computer once you want to do more things
than what the sort of visual interfaces you might be used to allow you to do.
可视化界面功能是十分局限的,
The visual interfaces are sort of limited in what they allow you to do,
因为你只能使用它所提供的的按钮、滑块、输入字段等功能.
because you can only do the things that there are buttons for, sliders for, input fields for.
而这些文本工具通常是相互可组合的，
Often, these textual tools are built to be both composable with one another,
可以使用许多不同的组合或编程方式进行自动化.
but also to have tons of different ways to combine them or ways to program and automate them.
这就是为什么，在本课程中，我们将专注于这些基于命令行或文本的工具，
And that is why, in this class, we will be focusing on these command line or text-based tools,
而Shell则是实现这些工作的主要工具之一。
and the shell is the place that you would do most of this work.
对于那些不熟悉 shell 的人，大多数平台也都提供一些形式的 shell。
So, for those of you who are not familiar with the shell, most platforms provide some kind of shell.
在 Windows 上，这通常是 PowerShell，但也有其他 shell 可用。
On Windows, this is often PowerShell, but there are also other shells available on windows.
在 Windows 和Linux 上，你会找到大量的终端。
On Windows ,on Linux, you will find tons of terminals.
这些是能显示 shell 的窗口，
These are windows that allow you to display shells,
并且你也会发现许多不同类型的 shell，
and you'll also find many different types of shells,
其中最常见的是 Bash 或 Bourne Again SHell。
the most common of which is Bash or the Bourne Again SHell.
由于Bash是非常常见的Shell，因此它也是我们在这些讲座中要重点介绍的。
Because it's such a common shell, it is the one we're primarily going to be covering in these lectures.
如果你使用的是 Mac OS 系统，你也可能拥有 Bash,
If you're on Mac OS, you will probably also have Bash,
但是打开终端应用程序时可能会出现一个较旧的版本。
maybe an older version of it, if you open the terminal app.
因此，如果你想在任何这些平台上跟随学习，可以自由选择，
And so, if you want to follow along on any of these platforms, feel free,
但请记住，尽管这些工具在所有平台上都有效，但我们的教学大多数是面向 Linux 的。
but keep in mind that most of this is gonna be sort of Linux-centric
尽管这些工具在所有平台上都有效
in terms of how we teach it, even though most of these tools work on all the platforms.
如果你想安装终端和 shell，但不知道该怎么做，
If you want to install a terminal and a shell, and you don't know how to do it,
我们很乐意在办公时间为你展示，
well, we're happy to show you at office hours,
或者你也可以简单地在 Google 上搜索你的平台加"terminal"，你就可以找到教程。
or it's usually very easy to just Google like your platform plus like "terminal", and you will get one.
现在，当你打开一个终端，你会看到一个类似于这样的界面。
Now, when you open a terminal, you get something that looks a little bit like this.
通常它只有一行在顶部，这就是所谓的 shell 提示符。
So, it will usually have just a single line at the top, and this is what's known as the shell prompt.
你可以看到我的 shell 提示符看起来像这样，
You can see that my shell prompt looks like this,
它包含了我的用户名、我所在机器的名称、
it has my user name, the name of the machine that I'm on,
我当前所在的路径（我们稍后会讨论路径），
the current path I'm on (and we will talk about paths a little bit later),
以及闪烁的光标在等待我的输入。
and then it's really just sort of blinking there, asking me for input.
这就是 shell 提示符，你可以告诉 shell 你想让它做什么。
And this is the shell prompt, where you tell the shell what you want it to do.
你可以自定义这个提示符。
And you can customize this prompt a lot.
当你在你的机器上打开它时，它可能不会完全像这样。
And when you open it on your machine, it might not look exactly like this.
如果你配置了一些东西，它可能看起来像这样，或者会呈现出各种各样不同的样子。
It might look something like this if you've configured it a little, or it might look all sorts of different ways.
我们不会在这个讲座中太多地讨论自定义你的 shell，
We won't go too much into customizing your shell in this particular lecture.
我们将在以后讨论。
We'll do that later.
这里，我们只会谈论如何使用这个 shell 来做有用的事情。
Here, we're just going to talk about how do you use this shell to do useful things.
这是你与计算机交互的主要文本界面。
And this is our the main textual interface you have to your computer through this shell.
通过这个 shell 提示符，你可以输入命令。
On the shell prompt, you get to write commands.
命令通常是相对简单的东西。
And commands can be relatively straightforward things.
通常会是像使用参数执行程序之类的事情。
Usually, it'll be something like executing programs with arguments.
这是什么样子的呢？我们可以执行一个名为"date"的程序。
What does that look like? Well, one program we can execute is the "date" program.
只需要输入"date"，按下回车，然后它会显示日期和时间。
We just type "date" and press enter, and then it will show you, unsurprisingly, the date and time.
你也可以执行带有参数的程序。
You can also execute a program with arguments.
这是修改程序行为的一种方式。
This is one way to modify the behavior of the program.
例如，有一个名为"echo"的程序，
So for example, there is a program called `echo`,
它只是打印出你给它的参数。
and "echo" just prints out the arguments that you give it.
参数只是跟随程序名的以空格分隔的东西。
And arguments are just whitespace-separated things that follow the program name.
所以我们可以说"hello"，然后它会打印出"hello"。
So we can say "hello", and then it will print "hello" back.
也许不是多神奇，但这就是参数的基础。
Perhaps not terribly surprising, but this is the very basics of arguments.
你会注意到我说参数是由空格分隔的，
One thing that you'll notice is that I said that arguments are separated by whitespace,
你可能会想，如果我想要一个由多个单词组成的参数怎么办？
and you might wonder, well, what if I want an argument as multiple words?
你可以使用引号括起来，
You can also quote things,
所以你可以做像`echo "Hello world"`这样的事情，
so you can do things like 'echo "Hello world"',
现在"echo"程序接收到一个包含带有空格的字符串"hello world"的参数。
and now the "echo" program receives one argument that contains the string "hello world" with a space.
你也可以用单引号来做这件事，
Well, you can also use single quotes for this,
我们会在讨论 bash 脚本时提及单引号和双引号之间的区别。
and the difference between single quotes and double quotes will get back to when we talk about bash scripting.
你也可以转义单个字符。
You can also just escape single characters.
例如，"Hello\ World"，这也可以正常工作。
So, for example, "Hello\ World", this will also work just fine.
我们稍后会涵盖有关如何转义和解析各种参数和变量的规则。
All of these rules about how you escape
and how you parse and quote various arguments and variables we'll cover a little bit later.
希望你不会遇到太多奇怪的事情。
Hopefully, you won't run into too many oddities about this.
最起码需要记住用空格分隔参数，
Just keep in mind at least that spaces separate arguments,
所以如果你想做类似于创建名为"my photos"的目录这样的事情，
so if you want to do something like make a directory called "my photos",
你不能只输入`mkdir my photos`。
you can't just type like "mkdir my photos".
它会创建两个目录，一个叫做"my"，另一个叫做"photos"，这可能不是你想要的。
It will create two directories, one called "my" and one called "photos", and that is probably not what you want.
现在，你可能会问，
Now, one thing you might ask is,
当我输入`date`或者输入`echo`时，shell是如何知道这些程序是啥，
how does the shell know what these programs are when I type `date` or when I type `echo`?
以及它们应该做什么呢？
How does it know what these programs are supposed to do?
答案是，你的计算机有一些内置程序，是你的计算机自带的。
And the answer to this is, your computer has a bunch of built-in programs that comes with the machine.
就像你一样，你的机器可能会附带终端应用程序，
Just like you, your machine might ship with like the terminal app,
或者附带Windows Explorer，
or it might ship with like Windows Explorer,
或者附带某种类型的浏览器。
or it might ship with some kind of browser.
它还附带了一堆面向终端的应用程序，
It also ships with a bunch of terminal-centric applications,
这些应用程序存储在你的文件系统中。
and these are stored on your file system.
你的shell有一种方法可以确定程序的位置。
And your shell has a way to determine where a program is located.
基本上，它有一种搜索程序的方式。
Basically, it has a way to search for programs.
它通过一种称为环境变量的东西来实现这一点。
It does this through something called an environment variable.
环境变量是一种变量，就像你可能习惯了编程语言中的变量一样。
An environment variable is a variable, like you might be used to for programming languages.
事实证明，shell，特别是Bourne Again Shell，真的是一种编程语言。
It turns out that the shell, and the Bourne Again Shell in particular, is really a programming language.
这里给出的提示不仅能够运行带有参数的程序，
This prompt that you're given here is not just able to run a program with arguments.
你还可以做类似于while循环，for循环，条件语句等的事情...
You can also do things like while loops, for loops, conditionals...
不仅如此,你甚至可以在shell中定义函数，变量
All of these, you can define functions, you can have variables,
所有这些事情都可以在shell中实现。
and all of these things you can do in the shell.
我们将在下一讲中讲解这些内容，即编写shell脚本。
We'll cover a lot of that in the next lecture, on shell scripting.
但是现在，让我们只看看这个特定的环境变量。
For now, though, let's just look at this particular environment variable.
环境变量是在启动shell时设置的东西；
Environment variables are things that are set whenever you start your shell;
它们不是你每次运行shell时都必须设置的东西。
they're not things you have to set every time you run your shell.
有一堆这样的变量已经被设置好了，
They are a bunch of these that are set,
例如你的主目录在哪里，你的用户名是什么，
things like where is your home directory, what is your username,
还有一个对于这个特定目的至关重要的变量，即路径变量。
and there's also one that's critical for this particular purpose, which is the path variable.
如果我运行`echo $PATH`，这将向我显示所有路径列表,shell就是在这些路径里搜索程序的。
So, if I "echo" out "$path", this is going to show me all of the paths on my machine that the shell will search for programs.
你会注意到这是一个用冒号(":")分隔的列表。
You'll notice that this is a list that is colon separated.
它可能有点长而且难以阅读，
It might be kind of long and hard to read,
但本质上是每当您键入程序的名称时，
but the essential is that bash whenever you type the name of a program,
它都会在计算机上搜索这个路径列表，
it's gonna search through this list of paths on your machine,
并在每个目录中查找与您尝试运行的命令匹配的程序或文件的名称。
and it's gonna look in each directory for a program or a file whose name matches the command you try to run.
因此，当我尝试运行`date`或`echo`时，
So, in my case, when I try to run "date" or "echo",
它将逐个遍历这些路径，
it's going to walk through these one at a time
直到找到名为"date"或"echo"的程序，
until it finds one that contains the program called "date" or "echo",
然后运行它。
and then it's going to run it.
如果我们想知道它实际运行的是哪个程序，有一个叫做`which`的命令可以让我们做到这一点。
If we want to know which one it actually runs, there's a command called "which" which lets us do that.
因此，我可以运行`which echo`，
So, I can type "which echo",
它会告诉我，如果我要运行一个名为`echo`的程序，
and it will tell me that if I were to run a program called `echo`,
我将运行这个。
I would run this one.
现在我们停下来谈谈路径是什么。
It's worth pausing here to talk about what paths are.
路径是一种命名计算机上文件位置的方式。
So, paths are a way to name the location of a file on your computer.
在Linux和macOS上，这些路径是由斜杠（正斜杠"/"）分隔的。
On Linux and macOS, these paths are separated by slashes (forward slashes).
因此，您会看到这是在根目录下，
So, you'll see here that this is in the root directory,
所以开头的斜杠表示从文件系统的顶部开始。
so the slash at the very beginning indicates that this is starting from the top of the file system.
然后查看名为"usr"的目录，然后查看名为"bin"的目录，
Then look inside the directory called "usr", then look inside the directory "bin",
然后查看名为"echo"的文件。
and then look for the file called "echo".
在Windows上，这样的路径通常用反斜杠("\")分隔。
On Windows, paths like this are usually separated by backslashes instead.
在Linux和macOS上，
We're on Linux and macOS,
所有内容都属于根命名空间，因此所有路径都以斜杠或绝对路径开头。
everything lives under the root namespace, so all paths start with a slash, or all absolute paths.
在Windows上，每个分区都有一个根目录，
On Windows, there is one root for every partition,
因此您可能已经看到过类似于"C:\" 或 "D:\" 的路径。
so you might have seen things like C colon backslash or D colon backslash.
因此，在Windows上，每个驱动器都有一个单独的文件系统路径层次结构，
So, Windows has separate file system path hierarchies for each drive that you have,
而在Linux和macOS上，所有这些都挂载在一个命名空间下。
whereas on Linux and macOS,  these are all mounted under one namespace.
你可能已经注意到我说了绝对路径这个词，你可能不知道它是什么意思。
You'll notice that I said the word absolute path, and you might not know what that means.
绝对路径是能完全确定文件位置的路径。
Absolute paths are paths that fully determine the location of a file.
因此，在此示例中，它仅针对特定的"echo"文件，
So, in this case, this is saying this is talking only about a specific "echo" file,
并提供了"echo"的完整路径，但也有相对路径。
and it's giving you the full path to that file, but there are also things known as relative paths.
相对路径是相对于您当前所在的位置，
A relative path is relative to where you currently are,
要找出当前位置，,可以运行`pwd`，它将打印出我当前所在的路径。
and the way we find out where we currently are is you can type "pwd" for present working directory.
现在?
Present?
打印工作目录，所以如果我键入 "pwd"，它将打印出我所在的当前路径。
Print working directory, so if I type "pwd", it will print out the current path that I'm in.
现在，我在根目录下的home目录中，然后是jon下的dev目录，等等。
Right ,so currently I'm in the home directory under the root and then jon under that and then dev under that, etc.
从这里，我可以选择更改我的当前工作目录，
From here, I can then choose to change my current working directory,
所有相对路径都是相对于当前工作目录而言的，
and all relative paths are relative to the current working directory,
这基本上是您所在的位置。
which is basically where you are.
在这个例子中，我可以运行`cd /home`。
In this case, for example, I can do "cd /home".
`cd`代表更改目录，这是我更改当前工作目录的方式。
"cd" stands for change directory; this is the way that I change what my current working directory is.
在这种情况下，我更改到home目录，您会看到我的shell提示符已显示我现在在home目录中了。
In this case, I change to home, and you'll see my shell prompt change to say that I am now in home.
它只给出了路径的最后一段名称，
It just gives me the name of the last segment of the path,
但您还可以配置终端，让它在任何地方都给您完整的路径。
but you can also configure your terminal to give you the full path whenever you're anywhere.
现在，如果我再次输入"pwd"，它会告诉我我在"/home"中。
And now if I type "pwd" again, it will tell me I'm in "/home".
还有几个特殊的目录存在："."和".."。
There are also a couple of special directories that exist. There is ".", and "..".
"."表示当前目录，".."表示父目录。
"." means the current directory, and ".." means the parent directory.
所以这是一个可以更方便切换目录的方式。
So this is a way that you can easily navigate around the system.
例如，如果我输入`cd ..`，
For example, if I type "cd ..",
它会告诉我我现在在"/"中，即我现在在文件系统的根目录中。
it will tell me that I am now in "/", so I'm now in the root of the file system.
我在"/home"中，现在我在"/"中，
I was in "/home", now I'm in "/",
如果我输入"pwd"，它会做正确的事情。
and indeed, if I type "pwd", it will do that right thing.
然后，我还可以使用相对路径进入文件系统，对吧？
And I can also then use relative paths to go down into the file system, right?
所以我可以运行`cd ./home`，
So I can do "cd ./home",
这将进入当前目录下的home目录，对吧？
and this is gonna cd into the home directory under the current directory, right?
所以这会把我带回到"/home"。
So this will bring me back to "/home".
如果我现在再试着`cd ./home`，它会说没有这样的目录，
If I now tried `cd ./home` again, it will say there's no such directory
因为当前目录下没有我要找的home目录，而我通过"cd"更改了当前目录。
because there is no home directory under the current directory I'm on, which I changed by doing "cd".
对吧
Right?
我可以使用相对路径"cd"一直返回到我使用相对路径的地方，
And I can "cd" all the way back to the place that I was using relative paths,
我也可以做类似"../../.."这样的事情，以回到我的文件系统的某个深处。
and I can also do things like "../../.." to get back to somewhere deep in my file system.
这恰好回到根目录，所以这里有一个"bin"目录，在"bin"目录中，有一个"echo"文件，
This happens to be all the way back to the root, so here there's a "bin" directory, and in the "bin", there's an "echo" file,
然后我可以做`echo world`，这将在"bin"下运行"echo"程序。
and so then I could do "echo world" and that runs the "echo" program under "bin".
所以这是一种可以构建路径以任意遍历文件系统的方法。
Alright, so this is a way that you can construct paths to arbitrarily traverse your filesystem.
有时您想使用绝对路径，有时您想使用相对路径。
Sometimes you want to use absolute paths, and sometimes you want relative ones.
通常，不管用哪个,我们总是希望使用最短的，
Usually, you want to use whichever one is shorter,
但是如果您想，例如，
but if you want to, for example,
运行一个程序或编写一个运行像"echo"或"date"这样的程序的程序，
run a program or write a program that runs the program like "echo" or "date",
并且希望它可以从任何地方运行，
and you want it to be able to be run from anywhere,
则要么只需给出程序的名称，如"date"或"echo"，
you either want to just give the name of the program like "date" or "echo"
让shell使用路径来找到它在哪里，
and let the shell use the path to figure out where it is,
要么给出其绝对路径，因为如果您给出相对路径，
or you want to give its absolute path because if you gave a relative path,
则如果我在我的主目录中运行它，而您在其他目录中运行它，
then if I ran it in my home directory and you ran it in some other directory,
我可能可以成功运行,而你不行。
it might work for me but not for you.
通常，当我们运行程序时，
In general, when we run a program,
它默认会在当前工作目录下进行操作，
it is going to be operating on the current working directory,
除非我们给出其他参数。
at least by default, unless we give it any other arguments.
这非常方便，因为它意味着我们通常不必提供完整路径，
And this is really handy because it means that often we don't have to give full paths for things,
我们只需使用文件名和当前所在的目录。
we can just use the name of files and the directory that we're currently in.
另外一个非常有用的技巧是查看当前目录中有哪些内容。
One thing that's really useful is to figure out what is in the current directory we're in.
所以我们已经看到了`pwd`命令，它会打印出您当前所在的位置。
So we already saw "pwd" which prints where you currently are.
有一个命令叫做`ls`，它会列出当前目录中的文件。
There's a command called "ls" which will show you, it will list the files in the current directory.
所以如果我在这里输入"ls"，这是当前目录中的所有文件，对吧？
So if I type "ls" here, this is all the files in the current directory, right?
这是一个快速浏览文件系统的方便方式。
And this is a handy way to just quickly navigate through the filesystem.
你会发现如果我执行`cd ..`,然后运行,`ls`,他会给我列出上一级目录的文件 。
You'll see that if I do "cd .." and then do "ls", it'll show me the files in that directory instead.
但是对于"ls"，我也可以用`ls ..`，我可以给它一个路径的参数，
But with "ls", I can also give it "ls .." like I can give it a path
然后它会列出给出路径的文件,而不是我当前所在的目录的文件，
and then it will "ls" that file instead of the one that I'm currently in,
或者"ls"那个目录。
or "ls" that directory.
你也可以看到这一点，如果我一直到根目录，对吧？根目录有不同的文件。
And you can see this if I go all the way to the root as well, right? Root has different files.
你可能不知道的一个方便技巧是有两个特殊的东西可以做。
One handy trick you might not know about here is there are two other special things you can do.
一个是波浪号字符("~")。
One is the tilde character.
"~"会将您带到您的主目录，
This character brings you to your home directory,
所以"~"总是扩展到主目录，
so tilde always expands to the home directory,
您可以利用"~"来写相对路径。
and you can do relative paths to it.
所以，我可以做 "~/dev/pdos/classes/missing-semester"，
So, I can do "~/dev/pdos/classes/missing-semester",
现在我在那里，因为波浪号扩展到"/home/jon"。
and now I'm there because tilde expanded to "/home/jon".
特别是对于"cd"，还有一个非常方便的参数，就是"-"。
There is also for "cd", in particular, a really handy argument you can give, which is "-".
如果你做`cd -`，它会切换到你之前所在的目录。
If you do "cd -", it will cd to the directory you were previously in.
所以，如果我做`cd -`，我回到了根目录。
So, if I do "cd -", I go back to root.
如果我再做`cd -`，我回到了missing semester。
If I do "cd -" again, I go back to missing semester.
这是一个方便的方法，如果你想在两个不同的目录之间切换。
This is a handy way if you want to toggle between two different directories.
在"ls"和"cd"命令中，还有很多其他的参数和选项可以使用。
In the case of "ls" or in the case of "cd", there might be arguments you don't know about. Right ?
现在，除了提供路径以外，我们还没有做任何事情，
Currently, we haven't really been doing anything except giving paths,
你怎么知道该怎样首先给"ls"一个路径吗？
but how do you even discover that you can give a path to "ls" in the first place?
大多数程序都会采用所谓的参数，如标志和选项。
Well, most programs take what are known as arguments, like flags and options.
这些标志和选项通常以"-"开头。
These are things that usually start with a "-".
其中一个方便的选项是"-help"。
One of the handy ones is "-help".
大多数程序都实现了这个选项，如果你运行，例如，`ls -help`，
Most programs implement this, and if you run, for example, "ls -help",
它会打印出关于该命令的大量帮助信息。
it will helpfully print out a bunch of information about that command.
在使用ls命令时，
And you'll see here that it says the usage is "ls",
你可以指定选项和文件。
and you can give some number of options and you can give some number of files.
usage中的"..."表示零个、一个或多个选项,
The way to read that usage line is triple dot means one like zero or one or more,
而"[]"表示可选项。
and the square bracket means optional.
因此，在这种情况下，选项和文件都是可选的。
So, in this case, there's an optional number of options, and there's an optional number of files.
你将看到程序的功能描述和各种可用的标志和选项的详细说明，你可以使用这些选项来控制命令的行为。
And you'll see that it says what the program does and also specifies a number of different types of flags and options you can give.
通常，我们称单个破折号("-")和单个字母的东西为标志(flag)，
Usually, we call things that are a single dash and a single letter a flag,
不带任何值的内容也是标志，
and anything that doesn't take a value, a flag,
带有值的东西为选项(option)。
and anything that does take a value, an option.
例如，"-a"和"-all"都是标志，"-C"或"-color"是选项。
So, for example, "-a" and "-all" are both flags, and "-C" or "-color" is an option.
如果你一直向下滚动，最终会看到一个“-l”标志.
One thing you'll see under here, if you scroll down far enough, is the "-l" flag.
嗯?不对.
And that's unhelpful.
"-l"标志被用来显示长列表格式。。
The "-l" flag uses a long listing format.
现在，这本身并不特别有用，但让我们看看它实际上是做什么的。
Now, that's not particularly helpful in and of itself, but let's see what it actually does.
所以，如果我输入`ls -l`，它仍然打印当前目录中的文件，
So, if I do "ls -l", it still prints the files in the current directory,
但它给我更多关于这些文件的信息。
but it gives me a lot more information about those files.
你会发现自己将经常使用这个功能，
And this is something you'll find yourself using quite a lot
因为它提供的额外信息通常非常有用。
because the additional information it gives you is often quite handy.
现在我们来看看这些信息。
Let's look at what some of that information is.
首先，在某些条目的开头的"d"表示这些条目是一个目录。
First of all, the "d" at the beginning of some of these entries indicate that something is a directory.
因此，这里的"_data"条目是一个目录，而HTML不是目录，它是一个文件。
So, the "_data" entry here, for example, is a directory, whereas for HTML is not a directory, it's a file.
之后的字母表示为该文件设置的权限。
The following letters after that indicate the permissions that are set for that file.
因此，正如我们之前所看到的，
So, like we saw earlier,
我可能无法打开特定的文件或无法进入特定的目录，
I might not be able to open a given file or I might not be able to cd into a given directory,
这取决于该文件或目录上设置的权限。
and this is all dictated by the permissions on that particular file or directory.
阅读这些的方法是，前三个字符的第一组是为文件的所有者设置的权限。
The way to read these is that the first group of three are the permissions are set for the owner of the file.
你会看到，所有这些文件都是我拥有的。
All of these files, you'll see, are owned by me.
第二组三个字符是为拥有该文件的组设置的权限。
The second group of three characters is for the permissions for the group that owns this file.
在这种情况下，所有这些文件也都是由jon组拥有的。
In this case, all of these files are also known by the jon group.
最后一组三个字符是其他人的权限列表。
And a final group of three is a list of the permissions for everyone else.
所以，对于那些不是文件或目录所有者或组所有者的人来说，
So, anyone who's not a user owner or a group owner,
这个目录可能有点无聊，因为所有的东西都是由我拥有的。
this directory is perhaps kind of boring because all of the things are owned by me.
但如果我们做一些类似于`cd /`和`ls -l`的操作，
But if we do something like "cd /" and do "ls -l",
你会看到这里所有的文件都是由root拥有的。
you'll see that here all of them are owned by root.
我们将在后面介绍root用户，
We'll get back to what the root user is,
但在这里你会看到一些更有趣的权限。
but here you see some of the permissions are a little bit more interesting.
每三个字符为一组,分别是读取、写入和执行。
The groups of three are read, write, and execute.
这些对文件和目录的含义不同。
What these mean differs for files and for directories.
对于文件来说，它很简单。
For files, it's pretty straightforward.
如果你对一个文件有读取权限，那么你可以阅读它的内容。
If you have read permissions on a file, then you can read its contents.
如果你对一个文件有写入权限，那么你可以保存文件，
If you have write permissions on a file, then you can save the file,
添加更多内容或完全替换它。
you can add more to it or you can replace it entirely.
如果你对文件有执行的权限
And if you have execute to the x bit on a file,
那么你就可以执行那个文件。
then you're allowed to execute that file.
因此，如果我们在"/bin"中执行`ls -l`,搞错了,应该是"/user/bin"，
So, if we do "ls -l" in "/bin", that's not helpful and "/user/bin",
你会发现所有的文件都已经设置了执行权限，
you'll see that all of them have the execute bit set,
即使对于不是文件所有者的人也是如此。
even for people who are not the owner of the file.
这是因为我们希望所有计算机上的人都能执行"echo"程序。
And this is because the "echo" program, for example, we want everyone on the computer to be able to execute.
没有理由只允许某些用户运行"echo"。
There's no reason to say only certain users can run "echo".
这没有任何意义。
That doesn't really make any make any sense.
然而，对于目录，这些权限有点不同。
For directories, though, these permissions are a little bit different.
因此，读取转换为"你是否被允许看到这个目录中的文件？"
So, read translates to "Are you allowed to see which files are inside this directory?"
因此，将读取权限视为目录的文件列表。
So, think of read as lists for a directory.
你是否被允许列出它的内容？
Are you allowed to list its contents?
对于目录的写入是指你是否被允许在该目录中重命名、创建或删除文件。
Write for a directory is whether you are allowed to rename, create, or remove files within that directory.
因此，它仍然有点正确，
So, it's still kind of right,
但请注意，这意味着如果你对一个文件有写入权限，
but notice that this means that if you have write permissions on a file
但你没有对它的目录有写入权限，你就不能删除该文件。
but you do not have write permissions on its directory, you cannot delete the file.
你可以清空它，但你不能删除它，因为这需要写入到目录本身。
You can empty it, but you cannot delete it because that would require writing to the directory itself.
最后，目录的执行权限对许多人来说是一个容易出错的地方。
And finally, execute on directories is something that trips people up a lot.
目录上的执行权限是所谓的搜索权限,
Execute on a directory is what's known as search,
这并不是一个非常有用的名称，但是这意味着：
and that's not terribly helpful a name, but what that means is:
你是否被允许进入该目录？
Are you allowed to enter this directory
如果您想要打开、读取或写入文件，
if you want to get to a file, if you want to open it or read it or write it, whatever you want to do,
如果要用"cd"进入一个目录，
basically, to cd into a directory,
您必须拥有该目录及其父目录上的所有父目录的执行权限。
you must have the execute permission on all parent directories of that directory and the directory itself.
例如,我要访问一个在"/usr/bin"的文件,比如"/usr/bin/echo"，
So, for example, for me to access a file inside "/usr/bin", such as "/usr/bin/echo",
我必须在根目录、
I must have executed on root,
"usr"目录和 "bin" 目录上都有执行权限。
I must have execute on "usr", and I must have execute on "bin".
如果我没有所有这些执行位，
If I do not have all those execute bits,
我将不被允许访问该文件，因为我将无法进入其中的目录。
I will not be allowed to access that file because I won't be able to enter the directories along the way.
您可能会遇到一些其他位，
There are a number of other bits that you might come across.
例如 "s" 或 "t"，
Like you might see "s"s or "t"s in these lists,
您可能会看到 "l"s，如果您感兴趣，我们可以在办公时间里讨论它们。
you might see "l"s, those we can talk about in office hours if you're curious.
它们大多数情况下对你在这个课程中所做的事情并不重要，
They will mostly not matter for anything you will do in this class,
但了解它们是很方便的。
but they are handy to know about.
所以，如果你对它们感兴趣，可以自己查阅或在办公时间来问我们。
So, if you're curious about them, look them up on your own or come ask us in office hours.
现在还有一些其他有用的程序要知道。
There are some other programs that are handy to know about.
哦，对不起，还有一件事儿需要说明，
Oh, sorry, there's one more  thing, as I mentioned,
如果只有一个"-"，那就意味着你没有该权限。
if you just have a dash it means you do not have that permission.
所以，如果它说，例如，我们在x位上有一个"-"，(这里老师应该说错了,是在w位上)
Right, so if it says, for example, our dash X,
这意味着你有读和执行权限，但没有写权限。
it means that you have read and execute, but you do not have right.
这个时候还有一些其他有用的程序要知道。
There are some other handy programs to know about at this point.
其中之一是move或`mv`命令。
One of them is move, or the "mv" command.
所以，如果我cd回到missing semester，这里的"mv"让我重命名文件。
So, if I cd back to missing semester, here "mv" lets me rename a file.
而重命名需要两个路径，它需要旧路径和新路径。
And rename here takes two paths, it takes the old path in the new path.
这意味着"mv"命令既可以重命名文件
This means that "mv" lets you both rename a file,
例如更改文件名但不更改目录，
like if you change the name of the file but not the directory,
也可以将文件移动到完全不同的目录中。
or it lets you move a file to a completely different directory.
只需要提供当前文件的路径和目标文件的路径，
It just you give the path to the current file and the path to where you want that file to be,
就可以改变它的位置和名称。
and that can change its location and its name.
例如，
So, for example,
我可以将"dotfiles.md"重命名为"foo.md".这个操作不会有任何输出，对吗？
I can move "dotfiles.md" to be "foo.md" unhelpfully, right?
同样，我也可以将它改回来。
And similarly, I can move it back.
还有`cp`命令，即复制文件，非常类似。
There's also the "cp" command, the "cp" or copy is very similar.
它让你复制一个文件。
It lets you copy a file.
"cp"也需要两个参数，
"cp" also takes two arguments,
一个是要复制的文件路径，一个是目标路径，这两个路径都要是完整路径。
it takes the path you want to copy from and the path you want to copy to, and these are full paths.
所以，例如，我可以使用这个命令来将"dotfiles.md"复制到"../food.md"，啊,对的,"food.md"。
So, I could use this, for example, to say I want to copy "dotfiles.md" to "../food.md", sure "food.md".
现在，如果我在当前目录下输入`ls ..`，你会看到那个目录下有一个叫做"food.md"的文件。
And now, if I do "ls ..", you'll see that there's a "food.md" file in that directory.
因此，`cp`也需要两个路径，它们不必在同一个目录下。
So, "cp" as well take two paths, it does not have to be in the same directory.
同样地，还有一个`rm`命令可以让你删除文件，需要提供文件的路径。
And similarly, there's the "rm" command which lets you remove a file, and there ,too, you can give paths.
在这种情况下，我删除了"../food"。
In this case, I'm removing "../food".
需要注意的是，在Linux上，默认情况下，删除不会递归进行。
You should be aware, for removing, especially on Linux, removal is by default not recursive.
所以你不能使用`rm`删除一个目录。
So, you cannot remove a directory using "rm".
你可以使用"-r"标志进行递归删除，
You can pass the "-r" flag which lets you do a recursive remove
然后给出你想要删除的路径，它将删除路径下的所有内容。
and then give a path that you want to remove and it will remove everything below it.
还有一个`rmdir`命令可以让你删除一个目录，
There is also the `rmdir` command which lets you remove a directory,
但它只能删除空目录。
but it only lets you remove that directory if it is empty.
这个命令的思想是作为一个安全机制，
So, the idea here is to sort of be a safety mechanism for you
以防止你不小心扔掉了一堆文件。
so you don't accidentally throw away a bunch of your files.
最后一个小命令很方便，那就是`mkdir`，
And the final little command that's handy to use is `mkdir`,
它可以让你创建一个新目录。
which lets you create a new directory.
正如我们之前讨论的那样，你不应该这样做，
And as we talked about before, you don't want to do something like this
因为它会为你创建两个目录，一个叫做"my"，另一个叫做"photos"。
because it will create two directories for you, one called "my" and one called "photos".
如果你真的想创建这样一个目录，
If you actually want to create a directory like this,
你应该使用反斜杠转义空格或者用引号引起来。
you would either escape the space or quote the string.
如果你想要更多关于任何命令在这些平台上如何工作的信息，
If you ever want more information about how any command to basically on these platforms work,
那么还有一个非常方便的命令。
there's a really handy command for that as well.
这个命令叫做`man`，用于手册页。
There is the program called "man" for manual pages.
这个程序以另一个程序的名称作为参数，并给出它的手册页。
This program takes as an argument the name of another program and gives you its manual page.
因此，例如，我们可以使用`man ls`来查看"ls"的手册页。
So, for example, we could do "man ls" and this shows us a manual page for "ls".
你会注意到，在"ls"的情况下，手册页提供了与 `ls -help` 得到的信息相似
You'll notice that in the case of "ls", it is fairly similar to what we got with "ls - help",
但更容易浏览、更容易阅读的格式。
but it's a little easier to navigate, a little easier to read.
通常在底部，你还会找到示例、
Usually towards the bottom, you will also get examples,
编写者信息、更多信息的位置等信息。
information about who wrote it, where you can find more information, and that sort of stuff.
有一件有时可能会令人困惑的事情，
One thing that can be confusing sometimes,
直到最近的一个版本加入了底部的"q to quit"的三个字，
at least until a recent version where they added this three at the bottom which says "q to quit",
它们以前没有这么说。
they do not use to say this.
你可以按 "q" 退出该程序。
You press "q" to quit this program.
如果你不知道这个便捷的键盘快捷方式，退出它可能会很困难。
It can be really hard to quit it if you do not know that.
顺便说一下，"Ctrl+L" 是一个便捷的键盘快捷方式，它可以清除终端并回到顶部。
A handy keyboard shortcut here, by the way, is "Ctrl+L", which lets you clear your terminal and go back to the top.
到目前为止，我们只讨论了单独运行程序的情况。
So far, we've only talked about programs in isolation,
但是当你开始组合不同的程序时，shell的大部分强大功能就会真正体现出来。
but where much of the power of the shell really comes through is once you start combining different programs.
你可能希望将多个程序链接在一起，而不是仅仅运行 `cd`，运行 `ls` 等等。
Right, so rather than just like running "cd", running "ls", and etc.,
你还可能希望与文件交互，
you might want to chain multiple programs together.
并让文件在不同程序之间传输。
You might want to interact with files and have files operate in between programs.
这时，我们可以使用shell提供的流的概念来实现。
And the way we can do this is using this notion of streams that the shell gives us.
每个程序都有两个主要的流：
Every program by default has, I'm gonna simplify a little and say, two primary streams.
输入流和输出流。
It has an input stream and an output stream.
默认情况下，输入流来自于键盘，
By default, the input stream is your keyboard.
基本上是你的终端，
Basically, the input stream is your terminal,
你在终端中输入的任何内容都会进入程序，
and whatever you type into your terminal is going to end up in the program,
而输出流则是每当程序打印输出时，输出的内容就会传递到这个流中。
and it has a default output stream, which is whenever the program prints something,
默认情况下，输出流也是指向你的终端的。
it's gonna print to that stream, and by default, that is also your terminal.
这就是为什么当我输入 "echo hello" 时，
This is why when I type "echo hello",
它会被打印回我的终端，
it gets printed back to my terminal,
但是，shell也提供了一种重定向这些流的方法，以改变程序的输入/输出指向。
but the shell gives you a way to rewire these streams, to change where the input/output of a programmer pointed.
最简单的方法是使用尖括号符号（"<>"）。
The way the most straightforward way you do this is using the angle bracket signs.
因此，你可以像这样写，或者像这样写。
So you can write something like this, or you can write something like this.
"<"表示将这个程序的输入重定向为这个文件的内容，
The left angle bracket indicates rewire the input for this program to be the contents of this file,
">"表示将前面程序的输出重定向到这个文件中。
and the end angle bracket means rewire the output of the preceding program into this file.
所以让我们看一个例子。
So let's look at an example of what that would look like.
如果我输入"echo hello"，我可以把"hello"
If I do "echo hello", I can say I want that context,
存储在一个名为 "hello.txt" 的文件中，
the content to be stored in a file called "hello.txt",
因为我给出的是相对路径，这将在当前目录中构建一个名为 "hello.txt" 的文件，
and because I gave this as a relative path, this will construct a file in the current directory called "hello.txt",
至少在理论上，它的内容应该是单词"hello"。
and at least in theory, its contents should be the word "hello".
如果我运行这个命令，你会注意到没有任何东西打印到我的输出中。
So if I run this, notice that nothing got printed to my output.
之前当我运行 `echo hello` 时，它打印出了 "hello"。
The previous time when I ran "echo hello", it printed "hello".
现在"hello"已经进入一个名为 "hello.txt" 的文件，
Now that "hello" is gone into a file called "hello.txt",
我可以使用叫做 "cat" 的程序来验证这一点。
and I can verify this by using the program called "cat".
`cat` 是一个打印文件内容的命令。
So "cat" prints the contents of a file.
比如，我可以输入命令 `cat hello.txt`，它就会显示出 "hello"。
So I can do `cat hello.txt`, and there it shows me "hello".
不过 `cat` 还有另一种功能，支持将输入与输出连在一起。
But `cat` is also something that supports this kind of wiring,
比如，我可以输入命令 "cat"，
so I can say "cat", which by default just prints its input,
默认情况下它只是将输入内容复制到输出中，
it just duplicates its input to its output,
但我可以告诉它从文件 "hello.txt" 中读取输入。
I can say I want you to take your input from 'hello.txt'.
此时，shell 会打开文件 "hello.txt"，
What will happen in this case is that the shell is going to open 'hello.txt',
读取其中的内容
take its contents,
并将其设置为 "cat" 命令的输入，
and set that to be the input of "cat",
"cat" 将其输出，
and then "cat" is going to just print that to its output,
因为我没有将输出重定向,所以输出将会显示在终端上。
which since I haven't rewired it is gonna be my terminal.
这样，"hello" 就会被打印到输出中。我也可以同时使用这两种方法。
So this will just print "hello" to the output, and I can use both of these at the same time.
比如，如果我想复制一个文件，
So, for example, if I want to copy a file,
但不想使用 `cp` 命令，
and I don't want to use the "cp" command for some reason,
我可以使用 `cat` 命令。在这种情况下，我什么也没告诉 `cat` 命令，
I can do this, and in this case, I'm telling the "cat" program nothing at all,
只是让它按照默认方式运行。
I'm just saying do your normal thing.
`cat` 命令并不知道这个重定向操作，
Right, the `cat` program does not know anything about this redirection,
但是我告诉 shell 使用 "hello.txt" 作为 "cat" 命令的输入，并将 "cat" 命令打印的任何内容写入 "hello2.txt"。
but I'm telling the shell to use "hello.txt" as the input for cat and to write anything that "cat" prints to "hello2.txt".
同样，这并不会将任何内容打印到我的终端上。
Again, this prints nothing to my terminal.
但是，如果我输入 `cat hello2.txt`，就会得到我预期的输出，即原始文件的副本。
But if I `cat hello2.txt`, I get the output as I would have expected, which is a copy of the original file.
还有一种双向箭头(">>")，它表示追加而不是覆盖，
There is also a double end bracket which is append instead of just overwrite,
所以如果我执行 `cat  hello2.txt`，
so you'll notice that if I do `cat  hello2.txt` again,
然后执行 `cat hello2.txt`，它仍然只包含 "hello"，即使它已经包含了 "hello"。
and then I cat hello2.txt, it still just contains "hello", even though it already contained "hello".
如果我把后面的">"改成">>"，就表示追加。
If I switch that to instead be a double end bracket,
现在，如果我查看该文件，它就包含了两个 "hello"。
it means append, and if I now cat that file, it has "hello" twice.
这些命令通常只是与文件交互的简单方法，
These are pretty straightforward, they're usually just ways to interact with files,
但当涉及到 shell 提供的另一个运算符，即管道符时，它们就变得更加有趣了。
but where it gets really interesting is an additional operator the shell gives you called the pipe character.
管道符就是一根竖杠("|")，
So, pipe is just a vertical bar,
它的作用是将左边程序的输出作为右边程序的输入。
and what pipe means is take the output of the program to the left
and make it the input of the program to the right, right?
比如，以 `ls /` 或 `ls -l /` 为例，
So, what does this look like? Well, let's take the example of `ls /` or `ls -l /`.
它们会输出一些东西。
This prints a bunch of things.
如果我只想得到输出的最后一行，
Let's say that I only wanted the last line of this output.
可以使用一个叫做 `tail` 的命令，
Well, there's a command called `tail`,
它可以打印输入的最后 n 行，
and tail prints the last n lines of its input,
使用 "-n1" 参数（或者 --line=1）
and I can do "-n1", so this is a flag called 'n' you can also use "--lines" if you want to use it as a longer option,
在这里，这表示只打印最后一行。
but in this case, this is saying just print the last line.
我可以将这两个命令连在一起，
And I can wire these together,
比如输入命令 `ls -l / | tail -n1`，
so I can say "ls -l / | tail -n1",
注意到这里的"ls" 不知道 "tail"，
and notice here that "ls" does not know about "tail",
"tail" 也不知道 "ls".
and "tail" does not know about "ls".
它们是不同的程序，从未被编程为彼此兼容。
They are different programs and have never been programmed to be compatible with one another.
它们只知道如何从输入读取并写入输出，
All they know how to do is read from input and write to output,
然后管道将它们连接在一起，在这种情况下，
and then the pipe is what wires them together, and in this particular case,
希望"ls"的输出成为"tail"的输入，
I'm saying I want the output of "ls" to be the input to "tail",
然后想要"tail"的输出仅流到我的终端，因为我没有重定向它。
and then I want the output of 'tail' to just go to my terminal because I haven't rewired it.
我也可以重新连接它，以便输出到"ls.txt"，
I could also rewire this to say I want the output to go to "ls.txt",
在这种情况下，如果我运行`cat ls.txt`，就会得到适当的输出。
and in this case, if I "cat ls.txt", I would get the appropriate output.
事实证明，你可以用这个做一些非常有趣的事情。
And it turns out you can do some really neat things with this.
我们将在数据整理讲座中详细介绍这个问题，
We're gonna cover this a lot more in the data wrangling lecture
大概在四天后，还会讲述一些high level内容
there will be in like four days  or something on the kind of fancy stuff you can do
例如开始构建先进的管道。
when you start building more advanced pipelines.
比如，
One to give you one example,
我们可以做类似于`curl --head --silent google.com`的东西，
we can do something like "curl --head --silent google.com"
就像这样
so just to show you what that looks like,
就可以给我所有访问google.com的HTTP头，
this gives me all the HTTP headers for accessing google.com,
然后我可以将其管道传输到"grep -a"（例如加上 "--ignore-case" 参数或者使用"-i content-length"参数来获取内容长度），
and I can pipe that to "grep -a" (like "--ignore-case" or just "-i content-length" if I want content length),
这样就可以打印出 HTTP 头信息中的内容长度。
so this is gonna print the content length header.
"grep"是一个程序，我们稍后会谈到，
"grep" is a program that we'll talk about later,
它可以让你在输入流中搜索指定的关键字。
they'll let you search in an input stream for a given keyword.
我们可以将其和 "cut" 命令一起使用，
We can pipe that through say, the "cut" command,
将分隔符设置为空格，并仅保留第二个字段，
which takes a delimiter set that to be space, and I want the second field,
这样就只打印了内容长度。
and this prints just the content length.
这个例子可能有点无聊，对吧？
This is sort of a silly example, right?
因为你只是从命令行中提取了 google.com 的字节数，
Like this just lets you extract the content length in bytes of google.com from the command line.
这并不是一个非常有用的事情。
It's not a very useful thing to do,
但你可以看到通过将它们连接在一起，
but you can see how by chaining these together
你可以实现一堆真正有趣的文本操作效果。
you can achieve a bunch of really interesting text manipulation effects.
事实证明，管道不仅适用于文本数据，你也可以对图像等东西使用它们。
And it turns out pipes are not just for textual data, you can do this for things like images as well.
你可以有一个程序，用于处理其输入上的二进制图像，并将二进制图像写入其输出，
You can have a program that manipulates a binary image on its input and writes a binary image to its output,
然后可以将这些程序通过管道链接在一起。
and you can chain them together in this way.
我们在以后的课程会讨论一些这种类型的例子.甚至可以用于视频。
And we'll talk about some of those kinds of examples later on,to0. You can even do this for video if you want.
你可以通过管道进行数据流传输。比如说，如果你家里有 Chromecast，
You can stream; this is, for example, a great way if you have a Chromecast at home.
你可以将最后一个程序作为 Chromecast 发送程序，在管道中将视频文件传输到它中，
You can stream a video file like this by having the last program in your pipe be a Chromecast send program.
它会以流或 HTTP 的形式传输视频文件到你的 Chromecast 上。
So you stream a video file into it, and it streams or HTTP to your Chromecast.
我们将在数据整理课程中更详细地讲解这个。
We'll talk a lot more about this in the data wrangling lecture.
但是还有一件事情，我想和你们讨论，
But there's one more thing that I wanted to talk to you about
关于如何以更有趣、
sort of how to use the terminal in a more interesting
更强大的方式使用终端，
and perhaps more powerful way that you might be used to.
这也许会对那些已经对终端感到舒适的人来说很有趣。
And this is perhaps even going to be interesting for the ones of you
who feel like you're already comfortable with the term,
但首先，我们需要讨论 Linux 系统和 macOS 系统中的一个重要主题，
but first, we need to cover an important topic when it comes to Linux systems and macOS systems, in particular,
即 root 用户的概念。
which is the notion of the root user.
root 用户有点像 Windows 上的管理员用户，它的用户 ID 是零。
The root user is sort of like the administrator user on Windows, and it has user IDs zero.
root 用户是特殊的，因为它可以在你的系统上随意做任何事情，
The root user is special because it is allowed to do whatever it wants on your system,
即使某个文件对任何人都不可读或不可写，
even if a file is not readable by anyone, or if it's not writable by anyone,
root 仍然可以访问该文件。
root can still access that file.
root 是一个超级用户，可以做任何想做的事情，
Root is sort of a super user that gets to do whatever they want,
但大多数时间，你不会作为超级用户来操作。
and most of the time, you will not be operating as the super user.
你不会成为 root 用户。
You will not be root.
你会像jon或者其他你的名字一样成为一个用户，
You will be a user like jon or whatever your name is,
这将是你常规情况下使用的用户。
and that's going to be the user you act with
因为如果你一直以root用户的身份操作计算机，
because if you were operating your computer as the root user at all times,
如果运行了错误的程序，它们可能会彻底破坏你的计算机，
if you ran the wrong program, they could just completely destroy your computer,
你肯定不希望发生这种情况，对吧？
and you don't want that, right?
但偶尔你需要做一些需要使用root权限的事情。
But every now and again, you want to do something that requires that you are root.
通常情况下，你会使用一个叫做"sudo"的程序。
Usually, for these cases, you will use a program called "sudo".
"sudo"或"do as su"，这里的"su"指的是超级用户，因此这是一种以超级用户的方式执行以下操作的方法。
"sudo" or "do as su", and "su" in this case is Super User,
这是以超级用户的身份执行操作的一种方式。
so this is a way to do the following thing as the super user.
通常，你需要在终端中输入"sudo"和命令来使用它，
Usually, the way "sudo" works is you write "sudo" and then a command like you would normally on your terminal,
它将以root用户的身份运行该命令，
and it will just run that command as if you were root,
而不是你实际使用的用户身份。
as opposed to the user you actually are.
在哪些情况下可能需要使用这样的东西呢？
Where might you need something like this?
嗯，有许多特殊的文件系统在你的计算机上，
Well, there is a special, there are many special file system on your computer,
但特别的，有一个叫做sysfs的文件系统。
but in particular, there's one called sysfs.
如果你cd到"/sys"，这是一个全新的世界。
If you cd to "/sys", this is a whole new world.
这个文件系统实际上不是你计算机上的文件，
This file system is not actually files on your computer.
而是各种内核参数。
Instead, these are various kernel parameters.
内核就像是你的计算机的核心。
So the kernel is like basically the core of your computer.
通过这个文件系统，你可以通过看起来像文件的方式访问各种内核参数。
This is a way for you to access various kernel parameters through what looks like a file system.
你会看到，如果我进入"class/"，例如，
You'll see here that if I cd into "class/", for example,
它有许多不同类型的设备可以与之交互，
it has directories for a bunch of different types of devices
或者可以访问各种队列或各种内部奇怪的旋钮。
that I can interact with or various queues I can access or all sorts of weird knobs internally.
由于它们暴露为文件，
And because they're exposed as files,
这意味着我们可以使用到目前为止使用的所有工具来操作它们。
it means we can also use all the tools we've been using so far in order to manipulate them.
其中一个例子是，如果你进入`sys/class/backlight`，
One example of this is if you go into sys class backlight,
这会直接让你配置笔记本电脑的背光灯（如果你有的话）。
so this backlight directly and lets you configure the backlight on your laptop if you have one.
所以我可以进入`intel_backlight/`，这是一台Intel笔记本电脑。
So I can cd into `intel_backlight/`, this is an Intel laptop.
在这里面，你会看到有一个叫做"brightness"的文件，我可以cat这个文件，
Inside here, you'll see there's a file called "brightness", and I can cat the brightness;
这是屏幕当前的亮度。
this is the current brightness of my screen.
但不仅如此，我还可以修改它以改变屏幕的亮度。
But not only that, I can modify this too, in order to change the brightness of my screen.
那么，你可能在想我能做到什么，让我们先看一下这里的最高亮度
So, you might think that I could do, let's see what the max brightness is here.
好吧，所以他现在已经设置成最高亮度了。
Okay, so it's currently set to the max brightness.
所以你可能会认为我可以做一些像"让我们把它减半"或者其他什么的，例如"调到500亮度"这样的事情。
You might imagine that I could do something like if I do "echo" let's do half or something "echo 500 > brightness'.
如果我这样做，它会说"权限被拒绝"。
If I do this, it says permission denied.
我无法修改亮度，
I'm not allowed to modify brightness because,
因为要基本更改内核中的东西，
in order to basically change things in the kernel,
您需要成为管理员。
you need to be the administrator.
您可能会想到解决方法是编写`sudo echo 500`，
And you might imagine that the way to solve this is to write "sudo echo 500",
但我仍然会收到权限被拒绝的错误。
but I still get a permission denied error.
为什么呢？
But why is that?
因为正如我之前提到的那样，
It's because, as I mentioned before,
输入和输出的重定向不是程序所知道的。
these redirections of input and output is not something the programs know about.
当我们将"ls"传输到"tail"时，"tail"并不知道"ls"，而"ls"也不知道"tail"。
When we piped "ls" to "tail", "tail" did not know about "ls" and "ls" did not know about "tail".
这个通道和重定向是由shell设置的。
The pipe and the redirection was set up by the shell.
所以，在这种情况下，
So, in this case,
我告诉我的shell运行程序"sudo"并使用参数"echo"和"500"，
what's happening is I'm telling my shell to run the program "sudo" with the arguments "echo" and "500"
并将其输出发送到名为"brightness"的文件，
and send its output to the file called "brightness",
但是shell是打开"brightness"文件的东西，
but the shell is what is opening the "brightness" file.
不是"sudo"程序。
It is not the 'sudo' program.
所以，在这种情况下，
So, in this case,
作为我运行的shell
the shell, which is running as me,
尝试打开brightness文件进行写入，但是不允许这样做。
tries to open the brightness file for writing and it's not allowed to do that.
因此，我会收到权限被拒绝的错误。
Therefore, I get a permission denied error.
如果您搜索某些内容，
You might have seen this if you like
最终进入Stack Overflow并告诉您只需运行此命令即可看到它的效果，
search for something end up on Stack Overflow  and it tells you to just run this command
您可能已经看到了这个错误
and you'll see that it does something like they give you instructions
例如`# echo 1 > /sys/net/ipv4 forward`。
like "1 > /sys",what's an example, "net/ipv4 forward", for example.
如果您正在设置防火墙，
This is something you may have seen if you're setting up a firewall
此命令应该可以正常工作，因为这个小井号符号表示以root身份运行此命令。
and this command is intended to work because this little pound symbol indicates run this as root.
这是很少被解释的内容，但这就是井号("#")的含义。
This is something that is very rarely explained, but that is what the pound symbol means.
您可以看到我的提示符上有一个美元符号("$")，
You'll see on my prompt there's a dollar symbol instead,
而"$"表示您不是以root身份运行。
and the dollar indicates you are not running as root.
那么如何解决这个问题？
So, the question is how do I get around this well?
好吧，我可以切换到root终端，因此可以通过运行`sudo su`来执行此操作。
I could switch into a root terminal, so one way to do this is to run "sudo su".
`sudo su`表示以root身份运行以下命令，
"sudo su" is saying run the following command as root,
"su"是一个复杂的命令，可以让您有效地以超级用户身份获取一个shell。
and "su" is a complicated command that effectively gets you a shell as the super user.
所以，如果我这样做，输入我的密码，
So, if I do this, type my password,
那么现在您会看到用户名从"jon"变为"root"，
then now you'll see that the username at the beginning changed from "jon" to "root",
而提示符从"$"变为"#"。
and the prompt changed from a dollar to a pound.
如果我现在进入该文件，
If I now come in to that file,
如果我执行`echo 500 > brightness`，
if I do "echo 500 > brightness",
我的屏幕变得有点暗，但您看不到它，
my screen got a little dimmer but you can't see it,
您只需相信我，现在我没有收到错误。
you just have to trust me, and now I didn't get an error.
这是因为shell现在正在以root身份运行。
And this is because the shell is now running as root.
它不是以"jon"的身份运行，而是以root用户的身份运行，root用户允许打开此文件。
It is not running as "jon", and the root user is allowed to open this file.
但是，根据我们现在对终端的了解，
But, given our knowledge that we have of the terminal now,
除了以root的身份运行shell，还有一种方法,即
there's actually a way for us to do this without having to drop to a root shell, and that is as follows...
我猜是恢复到1060。
That's, I guess, restore it to 1060.
你看出这个方法和之前的不同了吗？
Do you see why this is different?
这里，我告诉我的终端运行`echo 1060`命令，
Here, I'm telling my shell to run the "echo 1060" command,
它会打印出1060，
which is gonna echo 1060,
然后我告诉它运行`sudo tee brightness`命令，
and I'm telling it to run the "sudo tee brightness" command,
并让它将"echo"的输出发送到"sudo tee"中。
and I'm telling you to send the output of "echo" into "sudo tee".
要理解这个过程，你需要知道`tee`命令的作用。
In order to understand this, you need to know what the "tee" command does.
`tee`命令会将输入内容写入一个文件，同时也将它输出到标准输出。
The "tee" command takes its input and writes it to a file but also to standard out.
因此，如果你想将一个日志文件保存起来以备之后查看，
So, tee is a convenient way if you have say a log file that you want to like send to a file to store for later,
但同时也想在屏幕上看到它，你就可以将其通过"tee"命令通道传输，
but you also want to see it to yourself, then you can pipe it through "tee",
给它一个文件名，它就会将输入的内容同时写入那个文件和你的屏幕上。
give it the name of a file and it will write whatever its input is both to that file and to your screen.
在这里，我利用了这个命令，
And here, I'm taking advantage of that program.
让"sudo tee"作为root用户运行，并将输出写入"brightness"文件中。
I'm saying run "tee" as root and have "tee" right into the "brightness" file.
因此，在这种情况下，打开"brightness"文件的程序"sudo tee"是作为root用户运行的，
And so, in this case, the "tee" program, which is what is opening the "brightness" file,
所以它是被允许的。
is running as root and so it is allowed to do.
如果我运行这个命令，虽然你看不到，
If I run this, it will now, again, you can't see,
但是现在屏幕的亮度已经变亮了，
but the brightness has been turned on by a laptop,
而且我也没有收到任何错误消息，我也不需要切换到root shell去运行命令，
and I don't get any errors, and I never had to drop into a root shell and run commands there,
因为这样做通常是有一定危险的。
which can often be somewhat dangerous.
如果你想更深入地了解这个文件系统，
If you want to explore this filesystem a little bit more,
你可以在里面浏览，
there's a lot of interesting stuff in here if you just start browsing around.
你会发现许多有趣的东西。
You can find all sorts of fun things.
例如，我们发现这里有一个有趣的"brightness"命令。
So, for example, we noticed that there was a fun "brightness" command here.
我想知道我还能设置什么其他的亮度。
I wonder what other kinds of brightness I can set.
因此，我可以使用`find`命令，我们也将在接下来的课程中讲解。
So, I can use the "find" command which we will also talk about in a coming lecture.
我不会在当前目录中查看任何名称有点像"brightness"的文件。
I wouldn't look on any file whose name it's a little like "brightness" in the current directory.
咦，这样不太有用。
That's unhelpful.
也许它们不是文件。
Maybe they're not files.
我拼写错了吗？
Did I misspell "brightness"?
那为什么这会出错呢？
Yeah, why is it being annoying?
好吧，它可能不想为我查找"brightness"
Oh, apparently it does not want to search for "brightness" for me.
幸运的是，我已经知道一个很方便的方法，
Oh well, luckily for you, I know of one already ,
那就是有一个名为"leds/"的子目录，而"leds/"也有亮度设置。
handy that there is a subdirectory called "leds/", and "leds/" have brightness too.
有哪些LED呢？
What kind of LEDs are there?
哦，有很多东西，例如滚动锁定LED。
Ooh, lots of things, for example, the scroll lock LED.
现在，大多数人可能不知道滚动锁定LED是什么，
Now, most of you probably don't know what the scroll lock LED is,
更不用说滚动锁定键了。
or much less what scroll lock is.
你可能已经在键盘上看到过一个名为滚动锁定的键，
You might have seen a key on your keyboard neighbor named scroll lock.
基本上没有人知道它的意义，也没有人真正使用它做任何事情。
Basically, no one knows what it means anymore, no one really uses it for anything.
它基本上只是一个死键和一个死LED。
It's mostly just a dead key and also a dead LED.
如果你想配置它，使得每次你收到电子邮件时，
What if you wanted to configure it so that every time you get email,
滚动锁定LED都会亮起来，因为没有其他原因它会亮起来，那该怎么办呢？
your scroll lock LED lights up because there's no other reason why it would light up?
如果我们进入到这个具有亮度设置的特定目录，并将其设置为零，
Well, if we seed you into this particular directory that has a brightness place and it's set to zero,
那么如果我写入一个一会发生什么呢？
well, what happens if I write one into it?
你可能不应该随意在此目录中的随机文件中写入随机数字，因为你会直接影响到你的内核。
You probably should not just be writing random numbers into random files in this directory because you are affecting your kernel directly.
了解这些文件的功能。
Like, look up what the files do.
在这种情况下，我已经准备好了安全眼镜，并且进行了足够的研究，
In this particular case, I have warned safety goggles, and I've done my research,
所以现在你看不到，但在我的键盘上，滚动锁定LED现在是亮着的。
so now you can't tell, but on my keyboard, the scroll lock LED is now lit.
因此，如果我编写了一个程序来检查邮件等内容，
So, now, if I wrote a program that  like, did some checking of mail and stuff,
并在结束时运行一个将一个写入该文件的程序，
I could have it at the end run a program that echoes one into this file,
那么我现在就有了一种方法，可以让我键盘上的LED指示我是否有新的电子邮件。
and now I have a way for my LED to my keyboard to indicate when I've new email.
此时，你应该大致了解如何在终端和shell中操作，
At this point, you should know roughly your way around the terminal,
并足够了解这些基本任务的原理。
around the shell, and know enough to accomplish these basic tasks, at least in theory.
现在，你不应该再需要使用点和单击接口来查找文件了。
Now，you shouldn't need to use like point-and-click interfaces to find files anymore.
你可能需要掌握一个剩余的技巧，那就是打开文件的能力。
There's one remaining trick you might need, and that is the ability to open a file.
到目前为止，我只告诉了你如何查找文件。
So far, I've only really given you ways to find files.
但你应该知道的一件事是"missing semester...", `xdg-open`。
But one thing you should know about is "missing semester...","xdg-open".
这可能仅适用于Linux。
This will probably only work on Linux.
在Mac OS上，我认为它只被称为"open"。在Windows上，谁知道呢？
On Mac OS, I think it's just called "open". On Windows, who knows?
`xdg-open`，你可以给出一个文件名，它将在适当的程序中打开它。
"xdg-open", you give the name of a file and it will open it in the appropriate program.
因此，如果你使用`xdg-open`打开一个HTML文件，它将打开你的浏览器并打开该文件。
So, if you do "xdg-open" an HTML file, that will open your browser and open that file.
一旦你有了这个程序，在理论上，
And once you have that program, in theory,
你应该不再需要打开finder窗口了。
you should no longer need to open like a finder window ever again.
你可能会因其他原因想要打开finder窗口，
You might want to for other reasons,
但在理论上，你可以使用我们今天学习的工具完成所有操作。
but in theory, you can accomplish it all using the tools that we've learned today.
对于你们中的一些人来说，这可能都很基础，
This might all seem relatively basic for some of you,
但正如我所提到的，这是我们现在知道shell如何工作的准备阶段，
but as I mentioned, this is sort of the ramp-up period of now we all know how the shell works,
而我们将在未来的讲座中大量使用这些知识，使用shell做真正有趣的事情。
and a lot of what we'll be doing in future lectures is using this knowledge to do really interesting things using the shell.
这是我们要使用的接口，所以我们都要了解它。
That's sort of the interface that we're going to be using, and so it's important we all know it.
我们下一节课会更多地讨论如何自动化这样的任务，
We're gonna talk a lot more in the next lecture about how to automate tasks like this,
如何编写脚本来运行一些程序，
how to write scripts that run a bunch of programs for you,
如何在终端中处理条件和循环，
and have to do things like conditionals and loops and stuff in your terminal,
或者运行一个程序直到它失败，
and do things like run a program until it fails,
这在你想运行一些测试套件直到它失败的情况下可能会很方便。
which can be handy in classes where you want to run something until your test suite fails, for example.
那就是下周的讲座主题。
So, that's the topic for next week's lecture.
你有问题吗？
Did you have a question?
你一直在演示的是这个"sys"目录，
Yeah, just relating to what you've been demoing this "sys" directory that
如果您为 WSL(Windows Subsystem for Linux)，大概只有当您进入Linux时才会工作。
presumably will only work if your drop into linux if you running windows subsystem for Linux.
这是个好问题。
That is a good question.
我不知道WSL是否会暴露sys文件系统。
I don't know whether the Windows subsystem for Linux will expose the sys file system.
如果它这样做了，它可能只暴露了很少一部分。
If it does, it probably only exposes a very small number of things.
可能是因为有...
It might because there are...
我不知道，你可以查一下。
I don't know, check it out.
你会发现，本讲座的讲义已经在线上了，
One thing you'll see is the lecture notes for this lecture are already online,
在文件的最底部有一些练习。
and at the very bottom of the file, there are a bunch of exercises.
其中一些相对容易，一些可能有点难，
Some of them are relatively easy, some of them are a little bit harder,
我们鼓励你尝试一下。
and what we encourage you to do is to take a stab at going through them.
如果你已经知道这些东西，应该会很快的。
If you know this stuff already, it should go really quickly.
如果你不知道，它可能会教你很多你可能不知道的东西。
If you don't, it might teach you a bunch of things that you might not realize you didn't know.
对于我们在讲座后要进行的办公时间，
And for the office hours that we're gonna do right after this lecture,
我们将乐意帮助你完成所有这些，
we will happily help you get through all of those,
或者如果在此过程中学习了其他命令，
or if there are other commands that you learn in the process,
你想更有效地使用它们，我们也会很乐意帮助你。
you want to know how to use more efficiently.
然后在明天的下一节课中，
And then in the next lecture, which is tomorrow,
我们将假定您已经知道练习将要教给您的内容。
we'll basically be assuming that you know the kind of stuff that the exercise is going to teach you.
网站上也有一个电子邮件地址，您可以发送问题，
There's also an email address on the website where you can send us questions
如果在办公时间结束后想到了问题。
if you think of something like after the office hours are finished.
结束前还有问题吗？没有？
Are there any questions before we end today? No?
好的，我们在Gates Building的九楼，32号楼有办公时间，大约五分钟后开始。
Alright, well, we will have office hours on the ninth floor of the Gates Building, building 32, in like five minutes.
好的，到时候见。
Sweet, see you there.